MELISSA J WOMACK

Phone: (512) 568-5185

Address: 7510 E Grand Ave, Apt 3322, Dallas, TX 75214

GitHub: https://github.com/Melissajwomack

Portfolio: https://melissajwomack.github.io/portfolio-v2/

Email: m.womack010101@gmail.com

Summary

M.S. graduate student in bioinformatics and computational biology - computer science track. Anticipated graduation date of May 2021. Focused on improving skills in programming, algorithm analysis, and data engineering. Previous military experience where I gained soft skills in teamwork, discipline, and adaptability.

Skills

• C++

CSS

• SQL

• Git/GitHub

- JavaScript
- Node.JS
- MongoDB

• MacOS/Linux/Windows

- HTML jQuery
- Object-Oriented Programming Microsoft Office

Certifications

Full Stack Web Development Certificate

July 2018 - Oct 2018

The University of Texas at Austin

 Curriculum included: MERN Stack, Agile Methodology, API Integration, Responsive Web Design, Git/GitHub, Heroku, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.JS, React.JS, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, and MySQL

Education

Master of Science in Bioinformatics and Computational Biology

Aug 2019 - Present

The University of Texas at Dallas, GPA - 3.61

Bachelor of Science in Microbiology

Aug 2015 – May of 2018

Texas State University, GPA – 3.76, magna cum laude

Relevant Coursework

- Algorithm Analysis and Data Structures
- Combinatorics and Graph Theory
- Advanced Calculus and Linear Algebra
- Web Programming Languages Spring 2021
- Computer Science
- Probability and Statistics for Data Science
- Machine Learning Spring 2021
- Database Design Spring 2021

Experience

Graduate Student Research

Feb 2020 - Dec 2020

University of Texas at Dallas, Dallas, TX

- Comparative genomics study of bacterial samples from postmenopausal women with chronic or recurrent urinary tract infections
- Developed skills in bash, scripting, data analytics, communication and project development

Microbiology Technician

Feb 2019 - Aug 2019

Clinical Pathology Laboratories, Austin, TX

- Processed and handled over 200 clinical samples a day while adhering to safety protocols and ensuring quality control
- Assisted in the identification of clinically relevant organisms using a wide array of biochemical tests

Veterinary Food Inspection Specialist

April 2007 - Oct 2015

United States Army

- Collaborated in creating and implementing a database that kept track of 9.3 million dollars of inventory
- Performed the inspection of food designed for human consumption and assisted veterinarians with animal medicine